

### CONTACT

Address: Paris, France

Email: cochenercamille@yahoo.fr

Tel: (+33) 06 71 46 78 07 Github: camillecochener LinkedIn: camillecochener

Website: camillecochener.github.io

Availability: March 2021

#### **SKILLS**

Machine Learning & Deep Learning

Statistics

Data Analysis

Data Visualization

**Data Engineering** 

GCP, AWS

R, Python, SQL Programming

Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn

Keras, TensorFlow API, PyTorch

Git, Linux, MacOS, Docker, MLFlow

Curious

Team player

Problem solving

Rigor

Communication

### **LANGUAGES**

- French (Native)
- English (Fluent)

### PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT

# Coursera Certificates:

- Deep Learning (CNN, Sequence Models, GAN) by deeplearning.ai
- Al for Medicine by deeplearning.ai
- Data Science Specialization by John Hopkins University

# Meet-up:

• Speaker (Paris Data Ladies, 2020 december edition on Computer Vision, 100 Data experts attended)

#### **HOBBIES**

# Sports:

# Others:

- Horse riding
- Yoga
- Fitness
- Watercolour • Tennis

Travel

Baking

Piano

# CAMILLE COCHENER

# **Data Scientist**

Data Scientist with a Post Master's Degree in Data Science and Big Data from Télécom Paris, with more than 3 years experience in consulting in Statistics and Data Science, as well as in Computer Vision. Three words to define myself: passionate, efficient and eager to share. I am looking for a Experienced Data Scientist position for March 2021.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

07/2020 -01/2021

lixo

## **DATA SCIENTIST - COMPUTER VISION**

**Lixo -** Startup created at the end of 2019 - 5 employees 6 months

In charge of the AI module of the Lixo solution.

- Improved object detection models to reach best performances
- Developed a method for background subtraction from images
- Optimised neural networks on a micro-computer
- Wrote scientific documents to obtain funding (FTE grant, i-Lab)

Results: Performance of the model +120%, deployed in production, +90K€ grant earned

01/2017 -07/2019 2 years.

7 months

### **DATA SCIENTIST CONSULTANT**

Consulting company: IT&M STATS (IT&M group)

Neuilly-sur-Seine, France

Agoranov, Paris, France

► ESSILOR INTERNATIONAL, R&D, Créteil, France (10 months)

Led the 1st Data Science project related to the analysis of historical data in order to optimize the TimeToMarket of anti-reflective products.

**ESSILOR** 

- Carried out an in-depth exploratory analysis in order to identify insights
- Identified machine signatures according to their operating parameters
- Predicted the colorimetric measurements of lenses according to machine parameters
- Developed a statistical methodology to identify malfunctioning
- Trained internal teams in analysis methods and programming

Results: Delivered an analytical report, highlighting areas of improvement regarding the data strategy of the company

► L'ORÉAL R&I, Chevilly-Larue, France (1 year, 6 months)

Supported the Scientific Computing team for day-to-day Data Science projects.

- Created predictive models between consumer, sensory and instrumental measures • Analysed the reproducibility and repeatability of instrumental measurements
- Segmented product spaces and analysed product efficiency
- Developed applications for routine laboratory analysis (RShiny, GWidgets)

Results: Deployment of 2 applications, +15 analysis and models delivered to laboratories.

▶ **DIVISION INTERNE IT&M STATS**, Neuilly-sur-Seine, France (2 years, 7 months)

In charge of fixed-price projects and R training.

• Mutuelle Chorum: Segmented a customer portfolio and predicted an appetence score

- Clarins Laboratories: Classifyied pores according to their size based on instrumental measurements
- Société Générale: Trained a team of Data Analysts on the dplyr and tidyr packages (R)

ĽORÉAL

03/2016 -**DATA SCIENTIST INTERN** 

09/2016 6 months

Clarins Laboratories

Pontoise France

Modeling the relationships between consumer perceptions and instrumental measurements of skin mechanical properties.

### **EDUCATION**

2019 -2020

### ▶ <u>Télécom Paris</u> - Post Master's Degree in Data Science & Big Data

Topics: Statistics, Machine Learning (supervised, unsupervised, Deep Learning...), Data Engineering (NoSQL, distributed systems, cloud storage and computing...), Data Visualization

2013 -2016

### ▶ Agrocampus Ouest - Engineer in Life Sciences, Data Science Specialization

Topics: Data Analysis applied to biological, marketing and agronomic data, Machine Learning, Programming, Data Visualization

2010 -2013

▶ Lycée Chaptal (Paris) - Preparatory school to enter the French Grandes Ecoles

# DATA SCIENCE / DATA ENGINEERING PROJECTS

2019 -2020

Carrefour-X AI & Retail Challenge - Rang 1/26: designed a local Marketing Mix Modeling analysis and prediction of the impact of marketing media on sales (ROI) - 2 months Tech: GCP, Big Query, Python, CatBoost, Dash, Shap, MMM

- Bike Sharing Predictions: predicted the number of bikes shared at a London bike station Tech: Python, Spark, Open data, Random Forests, Validation croisée
- GDELT: built a fast and resilient ETL to analyze GDELT data (2.5 TB) Tech: Cassandra, Spark, AWS, Zeppelin, ETL
- Kaggle Toxic Comment Classification: built a multi-label model to predict the toxicity of a comment using textual data from Wikipedia Tech: Deep Learning, NLP, Keras, Dash

### **AWARDS**

2016

Laureate Syntec Trophy: competition that rewards the best quantitative studies <u>Travel Award</u> obtained for speaking at the SPISE congress in Vietnam